
<novel title="theHobbit" subtitle="OrThere&amp;BackAgain" Author="Tolkien">
    <chapter n="5">
        <ChapterTitle>Riddles in the Dark</ChapterTitle>
        <p n="1">When <character forname="bilbo" surname="baggins"><race hobbit="shire"
                >Bilbo</race></character> opened his eyes, he wondered if he had; for it was just as
            dark as with them shut. No one was anywhere near him. Just imagine his fright! He could
            hear nothing, see nothing, and he could feel nothing <location cave="MistyMts">except
                the stone of the floor.</location></p>
        <p n="2">Very slowly he got up and groped about on all fours, till he touched the wall of
            the <location cave="MistyMts">tunnel</location>; but neither up nor down it could he
            find anything: nothing at all, no sign of <race orc="goblin" from="MistyMts"
                >goblins</race>, no sign of <race dwarf="dwarves" from="Erebor">dwarves</race>. His
            head was swimming, and he was far from certain even of the direction they had been going
            in when he had his fall. He guessed as well as he could, and crawled along for a good
            way, till suddenly his hand met what felt like <MagicItem type="ring" createdBy="sauron"
                >a tiny ring of cold metal</MagicItem> lying on the floor of the tunnel. It was a
            turning point in his career, but he did not know it. He put the <MagicItem type="ring"
                origin="sauron" use="invisible, evil," name="theOne">ring</MagicItem> in his pocket
            almost without thinking; certainly it did not seem of any particular use at the moment.
            He did not go much further, but sat down on the <location cave="MistyMts">cold
                floor</location> and gave himself up to complete miserableness, for a long while.
                <hobbits love="food">He thought of himself frying bacon and eggs in his own kitchen
                at home - for he could feel inside that it was high time for some meal or
                other</hobbits>; but that only made him miserabler.</p>
        <p n="3">He could not think what to do; nor could he think what had happened; or why he had
            been left behind; or why, if he had been left behind, the <race orc="goblin"
                from="MistyMts">goblins</race> had not caught him; or even why his head was so sore.
            The truth was he had been lying quiet, out of sight and out of mind, in a very dark
            corner for a long while.</p>
        <p n="4">After some time he felt for his <object for="smoking">pipe</object>. It was not
            broken, and that was something. Then he felt for his <object for="pipeWeed"
                >pouch</object>, and there was some tobacco in it, and that was something more. Then
            he felt for <object for="fire">matches</object> and he could not find any at all, and
            that shattered his hopes completely. Just as well for him, as he agreed when he came to
            his senses. Goodness knows what the striking of <object for="fire">matches</object> and
            the smell of <object for="smoking" altName="pipeWeed">tobacco</object> would have
            brought on him out of <location cave="MistyMts">dark holes in that horrible
                place</location>. Still at the moment he felt very crushed. But in slapping all his
            pockets and feeling all round himself for <object for="fire">matches</object> his hand
            came on <MagicalItem type="sword" origin="elves" name="sting">the hilt of his little
                sword - the little dagger</MagicalItem> that he got from the <race troll="hilltroll"
                >trolls</race>, and that he had quite forgotten; nor do the <race orc="goblin"
                from="MistyMts">goblins</race> seem to have noticed it, as he wore <MagicalItem
                type="sword" orgin="elves">it</MagicalItem> inside his <object type="pants"
                atlName="shortPants">breeches</object>.</p></chapter>
</novel>
